I'll see you again, mister.
. سوف أراك مرة أخرى ، سيدى
Stop that. Stop it!
! أوقفى ذلك . توقفى عن ذلك
What was all that about, eh? Eh?
لماذا كان كل ذلك ، لماذا ؟ لماذا ؟
-What's your problem? -Right. Just settle down now.
ما هى مشكلتك ؟ - . حسناً . فقط إهدأى الآن -
-Excuse me. -So sorry.
. عذراً - . آسف جداً -
-What! -What?
! ماذا  - ماذا ؟ -
What?
ماذا ؟
-Who are you? -Oh, brilliant.
من أنت ؟ - . رائع -
I mean, totally wrong, big emergency,
. أعنى ، خطأ تام ، حالة طوارئ كبيرة
universe goes bang in five minutes, but...
الكون سينفجر فى غضون ... خمس دقائق ، ولكن
-Brilliant! -I'm the Doctor. Who are you?
! رائع - أنا الـ (دكتور) . من أنت؟ -
-Yes, you are. You are the Doctor. -Yes, I am. I'm the Doctor.
. (نعم ، أنتَ . أنتَ الـ (دكتور - . (نعم أنا . أنا الـ (دكتور -
Oh, good for you, Doctor. Good for brilliant old you.
. (هذا أمر جيدٌ لك ، (دكتور . جيدٌ للـ (دكتور) الرائع القديم
Is there something wrong with you?
هل بِكَ شيئاً ما غير سليم ؟
Oh, there it goes, the frowny face. I remember that one.
. ها هوّ ، الوجه العابس . أتذكر هذا الوجه
Mind you, bit saggier than it ought to be. Hair's a bit greyer.
. أنظر إليك ، مترهل قليلاً أكثر مما يجب . الشعر رمادى قليلاً
That's 'cause of me, though.
. رغم أن هذا بسببى
Two of us together's shorted out the time differential.
. إثنان منا معاً يقلل من الفارق الزمنى
It should all snap back in place when we get you home.
كل شئ سيعود لمكانه مرة . أخرى عندما نُعيدك إلى البيت
Be able to close that coat again. But never mind that. Look at you!
لتكون قادراً على إغلاق هذا المعطف مرة ! أخرى ولكن لا تبالى بهذا . إنظر لحالك
The hat, the coat, the crickety cricket stuff, the stick of celery...
قبعة ، معطف ، أشياء الكريكيت . وزهره الكرفس
Brave choice, celery. But fair play to you,
اختيار شجاع ، الكرفس , ولكن تصرف سليم منك
not a lot of men can carry off a decorative vegetable.
ليس الكثير من الرجال . يمكنهم التحلى بالخضروات
Shut up!
! إخرس
There is something wrong with my Tardis
(هناك شيء ما خطأ مع بالـ (تارديس
and I've got to do something about it very, very quickly.
ويجب على القيام بشئ ما . سريعاً جداً , جداً حيال ذلك
And it would help, it really would help,
, وسوف يساعد ، حقاً سيساعد
if there wasn't some skinny idiot ranting in my face
إذا لم يكن هناك أحمق . نحيف يتبجح أمامى
about every single thing that happens to be in front of him.
. عن كل شئ حدث مصادفةً أمامه
-Ooh, okay. Sorry, Doctor. -Thank you.
. (حسناً . آسف ، يا (دكتور - . أشكرك -
-0Oh, the back of our head! -What?
! الجزء الخلفى من رأسنا - ماذا ؟ -
Sorry, sorry. It's not something you see every day, is it?
آسف ، آسف . ليس شيئاً تراه كل يوم ، أليس كذلك ؟
The back of your own head. Mind you, I can see why you wear a hat.
. الجزء الخلفى من رأسك . فهمت , أستطيع أن أرى لما ترتدى قبعة
I don't want to seem vain, but could you keep that on?
, لا أريد أن أبدو متباه ولكن هل يمكنك أن تظل مرتديها ؟
What have you done to my Tardis?
ماذا فعلت للـ (تارديس) ؟
You've changed the desktop theme, haven't you?
, "لقد غيرت واجهة "سطح المكتب أليس كذلك ؟
What's this one? Coral? It's worse than the leopard skin.
ما هذا ؟ شُعَب مُرجانية ؟ . إنه أسوأ من جلد النمر
Oh! And out they come, the brainy specs.
. ها قد ظهرت , المواصفات الدماغيه
You don't even need them. You just think they make you look a bit clever.
. أنت حتى لا تحتاج لها . تعتقد فقط أنها تجعلك تبدو ذكياً بعض الشئ
That's an alert. Level Five, indicating a temporal collision.
, هذا إنذار .  من المستوى الخامس . يشير إلى تصادم زمنى
It's like two Tardises have merged, but...
يبدو مثل إثنتين من ... الـ (تارديس) قد اندمجتا ، ولكن
There's definitely only one Tardis present.
ليس هناك بالتأكيد إلا . تارديس) واحده حاضره)
It's like two time zones at war in the heart of the Tardis.
مثل أثنتين من المناطق الزمنية . (فى حرب داخل قلب الـ (تارديس
That's a paradox.
. هذا تناقض
It could blow a hole in the space-time continuum the size of ...
يمكن أن يخلق حفرة فى ... تغير "الزمن - الفضاء" الحجمى
Well, actually, the exact size of Belgium.
, حسناً ، فى الواقع . نفس حجم "بلجيكا" بالضبط
That's a bit undramatic, isn't it? Belgium?
ذلك غير مثير بعض الشيء أليس كذلك ؟ "بلجيكا" ؟
-Need this? -No, I'm fine.
أتحتاج لهذا ؟ - . لا, أنا على ما يرام -
Oh, no, of course. You mostly went hands-free, didn't you?
. لا، بالطبع أنت فى الغالب لا تحتاج له، أليس كذلك ؟
Like, "I'm the Doctor. I can save the universe using a kettle and some string.
مثل ، '' أنا الـ (دكتور) . يمكننى إنقاز الكون بإستخدام غلاية وبعض الخيوط
“And look at me, I'm wearing a vegetable "
, وانظر إلىّ ... أنا أرتدي الخضروات
-Who are you? -Take a look.
من أنت ؟ - . إلق نظرة -
-Oh. Oh, no. -Oh, yes.
. لا - . نعم -
-You're... Oh, no, you're... -Here it comes, yeah. Yeah, I am.
... أنت ... لا , أنت - . ها هو , نعم . هو انا -
-A fan. -Yeah... What?
. مُعجَب - نعم ... ماذا ؟ -
Level 10 now. This is bad. A few minutes to Belgium.
. المستوى العاشر الآن . هذا سئ . "بضع دقائق لـ "بلجيكا
What do you mean, a fan? I'm not just a fan, I'm you.
ماذا تقصد ، مُعجَب ؟ . أنا لست مجرد مُعجَب ، أنا أنت
Okay, you're my biggest fan. Look, it's perfectly understandable.
. حسناً ، أنت أكبر مُعجَبى . أنظر ، هذا مفهوم تماماً
I go zooming around space and time, saving planets,
, أسافر عبر الفضاء والزمن , أنقذ الكواكب
fighting monsters and being...
... أقاتل الوحوش وأكون
Well, let's be honest, pretty sort of marvellous.
, حسناً ، دعونا نكون صادقين . بالتاكيد رائعاً
So naturally, now and then, people notice me. Start up their little groups.
. لذلك بطبيعة الحال ، الآن ومن وقت سابق ، يلاحظنى الناس . ويبدأون  فى تكوين جماعاتهم الصغيرة
That LI.N.D.A. lot. Are you one of them?
تلك L.I.N.D.A.جماعة هل أنت واحد منهم ؟
How did you get in here? Can't have you lot knowing where I live.
كيف وصلت إلى هنا ؟ . لا يمكنك أن تعرف الكثير عن مكان إقامتى
Listen to me. I'm you. I'm you with a new face.
. إستمع لى . أنا هو أنت . أنا هو أنت بوجه جديد
Check out this bone structure, Doctor,
, (تحقق من هذا التكوين العظمى ، (دكتور
'cause one day you're going to be shaving it.
. لإنه يوماً ما ستقوم بحلاقته
The cloister bell.
. جرس الدير
Yeah, right on time. That's my cue.
. نعم ، في الوقت المحدد . هذه إشارتى
In less than a minute, we're going to create a black hole
, في أقل من دقيقة سنكون بصدد خلق ثقب أسود
strong enough to swallow the entire universe.
. بقوة كافيه لإبتلاع الكون كله
Yeah, that's my fault actually. I was rebuilding the Tardis,
. نعم ، هذا فى الواقع خطأى , (كنت أعيد بناء الـ (تارديس
forgot to put the shields back up.
. نسيت أن أعيد وضع دعم الدروع
Your Tardis and my Tardis... Well, the same Tardis
الـ (تارديس) الخاصه بك و الـ (تارديس) , (الخاصه بى .. حسناً ، نفس الـ (تارديس
at different points in its own time stream collided,
, تتصادم فى نقاط مختلفة من مسارها الزمنى
and there you go, end of the universe, butterfingers.
, وها نحن بصدد . نهاية الكون ، أخرق
But don't worry, I know exactly how this all works out. Watch.
ولكن لا تقلق ، أنا أعلم بالضبط . كيف يعمل كل ذلك . راقب
Venting the thermo-buffer.
. تنفيس الظهير الحرارى
Roaring the Helmic Regulator!
! نضغط منظم الزمن والمكان
And just to finish off, let's fry those Ziton crystals.
, ولإنهاء الأمر . دعنا نقلى بلورات "زيتون" تلك
-You'll blow up the Tardis. -Only way out.
. (سوف تفجر الـ (تارديس - . الطريقة الوحيده -
-Who told you that? -You told me that.
من قال لك ذلك ؟ - . أنت قلت لى ذلك -
Supernova and black hole at the exact same instant.
إنفجار نَجمى وثقب أسود . فى نفس اللحظة بالضبط
-Explosion cancels out implosion. -Matter remains constant.
. إنفجار يلغى الأنضغاط الداخلى - . وتبقى الماده ثابته -
-Brilliant. -Far too brilliant.
. رائع - . رائع بدرجه عظيمه -
I've never met anyone else who could fly the Tardis like that.
لم ألتق من قبل بشخص  آخر . يمكنه الطيران بالـ  (تارديس) هكذا
Sorry, mate, you still haven't.
. آسف ، يا زميل ، أنت لا زالت كذلك
You didn't have time to work all that out. Even I couldn't do it.
. لم يكن لديك الوقت لتكتشف كل ذلك . حتى أنا لا يمكننى ذلك
I didn't work it out. I didn't have to.
. أنا لم أكتشف ذلك . لم يكن على أن أفعل
-You remembered. -Because you will remember.
. لقد تذكرت - . لأنك سوف تتذكر -
You remembered being me, watching you doing that.
, أنت تذكرت كونكَ أنا . مشاهدتك وأنت تفعل ذلك
You only knew what to do because I saw you do it.
أنت تعرف ما يجب القيام به . فقط لأننى رأيتك تفعل ذلك
Wibbly-wobbly...
... مُحير , مُحير
BOTH: Timey-wimey!
! مُحير , مُحير
Right! Tardises are separating. Sorry, Doctor. Time's up.
. حسناً ! كلا الـ (تارديس) تنفصلان . عذراً ، (دكتور) . إنتهى الوقت
Back to long ago. Where are you now?
العودة إلى فترة طويلة مضت . أين أنت الآن ؟
Nyssa and Tegan? Cybermen and Mara
"نيسا" و "تيجان" ؟ "سيبيرمن" و"مارا"
and Time Lords in funny hats and the Master?
و "سادة الزمن" يرتدون قبعات مضحكه والـ (ماستر) ؟
Oh, he just showed up again. Same as ever.
. إنه ظهر للتو مرة أخرى . كما هو دائماً
Oh, no. Really? Does he still have that rubbish beard?
لا . هل حقاً ؟ هل ما زال لديه تلك اللحية القبيحه ؟
No. No, beard this time. Well, a wife.
. لا . لا لحية هذه المرة . حسناً ، زوجة
Oh, I seem to be off. What can I say?
يبدو أننى سأغادر . ماذا أقول ؟
-Thank you, Doctor. -Thank you.
. (شكرا لك ، (دكتور - . شكرا لك -
I'm very welcome.
. أنا سعدت للغايه
You know, I love being you.
. أتَعلَم ، أنا أحببت كونى أنت
Back when I first started at the very beginning,
فى الماضى عندما بدأت , لأول مرة في البداية
I was always trying to be old and grumpy and important,
كنت أحاول دائماً أن أكون , أكبر سناً وغاضباً وذو أهميه
like you do when you're young.
. مثلما تفعل عندما تكون شاباً
And then I was you. And it was all dashing about and playing cricket,
ثم كُنت أنت . وكان كل ذلك , الأنطلاق ولعب الكريكيت
and my voice going all squeaky when I shouted. I still do that!
وصوتى يصبح صريراً ! عندما أصيح . ما زلت أفعل ذلك
The voice thing. I got that from you.
. أمر الصوت هذا . حصلت عليه مِنك
Oh, and the trainers and...
... والتدريب و
Snap.
. المفاجئة
"Cause you know what, Doctor?
لأنه أتعرف ، دكتور ؟
You were my Doctor.
. كنت الـ (دكتور) المفضل عندى
-To days to come. -All my love to long ago.
. لأيام قادمة - . كل حبي منذ فترة طويلة -
FIFTH DOCTOR: Oh, Doctor. Remember to put your shields up.
: الـ (دكتور) الخامس . تذكر وضع الدروع
(HORN BLARING)
ماذا ؟